

CONTACT

0468585718 mr.john.coote@gmail.com @johnofsydney www.linkedin.com/in/mrjohncoote/ johnofsydney.github.io

SUMMARY

I have several years of work experience in Electrical Engineering and Recruitment. I recently decided to re-train and make a career in web development.

I am seeking a junior web developer position in full stack or back-end development. I'm open to any kind of work environment that will allow me to further develop my skills.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive October 2017 - January 2018

SYDNEY UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

TEACHING ASSISTANT. FEBRUARY 2018 - PRESENT

After completing the Web Development Immersive course at General Assembly I was very pleased to be offered a contract to be Teacher's Assistant for the following class.

- Present the daily warm-up exercise live code the solution.
- Offer advice to students on all of the course material during labs and projects
- Debugging student's work
- Mark student's homework and projects

NEW SKILLS

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- JQuery & underscore
- Ruby & Rails
- Postegresql
- Sinatra
- APIs & JSON
- Bootstrap
- git/github

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

STUDENT. OCTOBER 2017 - JANUARY 2018

Full time course covering an introduction to programming, databases and various technologies required for junior full stack developer Projects include;

- Elemental database driven website with info on Elements, Scientists and Countries. Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Bootstrap, Google Charts and geoChart, Three.JS animations
- NORA Real Estate application & Group Project. Rails back-end, React front-end.
- FM_Booker like Uber for Facilities Maintenance companies. Rails, Javascript, Bootstrap, google Maps API
- Project 0 Games: Tic Tac Toe, Connect 4 and Othello. HMTL / CSS and Javascript

OLD SKILLS

- Small Business Management
- New Business Development
- MS Access / VBA
- MS SQL Server
- Translating business requirements into software
- Engineering Design (AutoCAD) and Project Management
- On site testing and commissioning
- Technical presentation
- Have used several MRP packages.

DATAHOUSESOFTWARE

DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT. 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2017

At the same time as I was running my recruitment business (see below) I developed and sold a recruitment database "Pipeline" suitable for running a small recruitment agency. Pipeline has been used by companies in Australia, NZ, UK, USA and South Africa. It is still available as freeware but I'm no longer actively developing new features.

- Microsoft Access. SQL Server. Visual Basic
- SQL Queries, including select, append, update, union.
- Hosting of customer databases on a virtual server (windows)
- Integration with Outlook (Email and Calendar) and 3rd party SMS providers
- Training and support to customers

www.datahousesoftware.com

EMERSON

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER. 2014 - 2015

Design, Production Engineering, Testing and Commissioning of standby power systems for the telecommunications industry

- AutoCAD for Electrical and Mechanical design.
- Cable sizing to AS 3000, voltage drop calculations, circuit breaker selection
- Metalwork design, sheet metal and copper bus-bars
- Power Electronics Rectifiers, Inverters, Converters and Controllers
- Programming of Monitor and Control Modules
- On-site testing and commissioning, including no break live cutovers
- Batteries, UPS, Transfer Switches
- Project Management of suppliers, customers, and factory.
- Technical Documentation

STAFFORD ISLAND

BUSINESS OWNER. 2006 - 2014

A recruitment agency sourcing candidates for the electrical engineering industry. My role covered business development, account management, advertising, wages, taxes, insurance. During the busiest years I had contractors in 3 states and a wage bill of ~\$900k pa .as well as making placements for permanent positions.

COMMAND RECRUITMENT

RECRUITMENT CONSULTANT. 2004 - 2006

Contract and permanent recruiting for the electrical engineering industry

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER. 1995 - 2004

Design, Production Engineering, Project Management, Testing and Commissioning of stand by power systems for the telecommunications industry. Most of my work was for a company called Com10 who are no longer in business.

INTERESTS

- Cricket I'm not very good, but I love to play, and could talk about cricket for hours.
 Everything is in balance; the perfect sport.
- Music I'm currently learning to play the banjo. My neighbours are probably not delighted.
- Reading History, History and more history. Modern History to Ancient History and all points in between. Endlessly fascinating and informative

Referees: on request